The ChirpStack installation will be very fast.
Whatever the hardware we've chosen to install the server,
the fact that we use a Docker container will make it very easy. For us,
it's time now to choose where we will set up our server.
We've seen many possible options.
It can be our local PC, a Raspberry Pi, a virtual machine, but in my case I'm going to use a public
server that I've rented from a cloud provider.
It's a simple machine with very few capabilities: 2 Giga Bytes of RAM and only one virtual Core.
But it will be more than enough for our demonstration.
Of course, as our network increases because for example we have new clients, then we can scale
it to increase its capacity.
If you've chosen to set up your server on another platform, no problem,
the demonstration will exactly be the same.
So, no worries. On my server,
I've installed a Basic Linux Debian Operating System.
Actually, to be honest I haven't done it myself
as my server provider propose many ready to use operating system and I picked up debian. And, the only
thing I've installed is as we've said several times, Docker and Docker-compose.
In addition to this private server,
I also have a domain name.
So if we want, instead of using the server IP address we can use the URL chirpstack.univ-lorawan.fr.
It's not compulsory, but I reckon it's clearer and more convenient.
If you only have an IP address available then no worries,
you can obviously use it.
So for this demonstration I connect to my Linux machine using SSH.
If you don't remember how to connect a remote machine using SSH, then please see the specific video
in the HOW TO section at the beginning of this course.
Here we go.
I've got a terminal from my remote Linux.
Okay.
Now if we look at the ChirpStack documentation.
Basically, the installation process is composed of three steps.
First, we need to download the ChirpStack container configuration file called docker-compose.yml.
We will also need the other configuration file that Docker will use to build the LoRaWAN server as it's
an open source server.
All these files are on the ChirpStack GitHub repository.
This step is easy. In ChirpStack documentation,
they provide the right command to download all files.
We just need to use it.
git clone and the repository address.
Then we enter the downloaded folder.
Right.
Now that we have all the necessary files, the second step is to apply our specific configuration.
We could configure the credentials to connect to the LoRaWAN  server.
We could enable or disable some region, but in our case that's going to be extremely easy because if
we leave the default values, these default configuration works out of the box.
Great.
So, let's launch the installation process.
We just need to use the command docker compose up.
I'm just going to add two things in the command.
First, the keyword sudo, because I use a Linux environment and I need to ask for privileges to execute
the docker compose command.
Secondly, I'm using the option -d because I want to leave ChirpStack running in the background,
otherwise I wouldn't be able to get my terminal back.
Okay, let's try that.
It takes a few seconds.
All containers are downloaded, extracted and created and my ChirpStack server is now ready.
It's not more complicated than that.
Now, we have all services running.
We can check them with another command.
docker ps.
There we go.
Everything is up and running. By default on ChirpStack,
if we want to have access to the user interface, then we need to use a web browser with the server
URL on port 8080.
But of course I could have used the IP address.
Okay, great.
And the default login and password is admin/admin and we are now logged on our new Network Server. As
it's a public server,
the first thing we need to do is obviously to update our password.
Okay.
Now that the installation process is done, let's present the ChirpStack network server interface.
On the left, the user interface has a menu with two parts.
On the top, it's the administrator menu.
It means that it's only available if we have privileges.
It's called the network server menu and of course we can access it because we have the administrator
login.
In this menu, we can configure the tenant, users and many other network properties.
There is already one tenant available by default.
It's called ChirpStack.
A tenant is a group of users and for each group, so for each tenant we can decide the number of gateways
and the number of devices it can register.
So, of course we can create another tenant.
And below, there is the number of gateway and devices the Network Server administrator will allow for
this tenant.
We can also change it later if we need to update some privileges to a specific tenant.
Okay.
In my case, I'm not going to add a new tenant to the list because for this demonstration we'll keep
the default value one called ChirpStack.
If we select a specific tenant.
So in our case ChirpStack, as it's the only one available, then we'll be able to create users.
In my case, I use the administrator login, so I don't need to create users.
But if you're a company and need several accounts on this server, then you will need to create as many
users as you want and assign specific rights and privileges.
Great.
Now, with the bottom menu, we'll be able to complete the usual process to register gateways, applications
and end-devices.
And that's what we're going to do in the next video.